好 别急着松手
Okay, hold on, don't shoot.
瞄准了吗
You see where you're going?
好 现在我们做点儿准备
Okay. Now, let's worry about how you get there.
过来一点儿 脚尖朝这边
Gotta move your foot here. Point your toe this way.
转过来点儿
Your hips here. Okay?
- 看得见吗 - 可以
- Can you see? - Yeah.
确定吗
Are you sure?
现在呢 还看得见吗
How about now? Can you see now?
挡住啦 那这样呢
No. How about now?
行了
All right.
准备好了吗 拉弓
Ready? Three fingers.
真棒
Nice!
好球 孩子
Nice throw, kiddo.
接着
Here you go.
你们是加蛋黄酱还是芥末酱 还是都要
Hey, you guys want mayo? Or mustard? Or both?
吃热狗谁加蛋黄酱啊
Who puts mayo on a hot dog?
没准你的兄弟要
Probably your brothers.
来两个加芥末酱的 谢谢啦 亲爱的
Uh, two mustard, please! Thanks, Mama.
收到
Got it!
奈特 蛋黄酱还是芥末酱
Nate, mayo or mustard?
番茄酱怎么样
How about ketchup?
番茄酱没问题 我也有
Or ketchup. I got ketchup, too.
注意肘部
Mind your elbow.
干得好 小鹰眼 去把箭拿回来
Good job, hawk-eye. Go get your arrow.
各位 练得差不多啦 饭好啦
Hey, guys! Enough practice. Soup's on!
好的 来啦 我们都饿了
All right. We're coming. We're hungry.
莱拉 走吧
Lila, let's go.
莱拉
Lila?
亲爱的
Honey?
孩子们
Hey, babe?
亲爱的
Babe?
孩子们
Boys!
劳拉
Laura!
你不必那样
You don't need to do that.
你保持这样就好
Because, uh, you're just holding the position.
来吧
Oh, yeah.
就差一点儿
That was close.
进了 我们现在一比一平了
That's a goal. We are now one apiece.
我想再试一次
I would like to try again.
现在平局 紧张不紧张 好玩儿吧
We're tied up. Feel the tension? It's fun.
糟糕 现在你有机会赢了
That was terrible. Now you have a chance to win.
这样你就赢了 恭喜
And you've won. Congratulations.
公平竞赛
Fair game.
友谊第一
Good sport.
好玩儿吗
You have fun?
好玩儿
It was fun.
启动了吗
This thing on?
波兹小姐 佩珀
Hey, Miss Potts. Pep.
你要是发现这段影像
If you find this recording...
可别发到网上去 这个太伤感了
don't post it on social media. It's gonna be a real tearjerker.
我不知道你能不能看见这些
I don't know if you're ever gonna see these.
我甚至不知道你是不是还…
I don't even know if you're still...
老天 希望你没事儿
Oh, God, I hope so.
今天是第二十一天了
Today's day 21.
不对 是第二十二天
No, uh, 22.
相比浩瀚的宇宙 我的存在微不足道
You know, if it wasn't for the existential terror  of staring into the literal void of space,
如果不细想 今天我过得还行
I'd say I'm feeling a little better today.
感染好多了 多亏了有蓝妹妹在这儿
Infection's run its course, thanks to the Blue Meanie back there.
你肯定会喜欢她的
Oh, you'd love her.
特别干练
Very practical.
就是下手有点儿重
Only a tiny bit sadistic.
燃料舱在作战时炸裂了
So, the fuel cells were cracked during battle...
我们想了个办法利用反向离子充电
and we figured out a way to reverse the ion charge...
争取了大概48小时的飞行时间
and bought ourselves about 48 hours of flight time.
但是现在没招了
Uh, but it's now dead in the water.
我们离最近的便利店还有几千光年呢
Thousand light years from the nearest 7-Eleven.
氧气只能支撑到明天早上
Oxygen will run out tomorrow morning...
然后就这样了
and that'll be it.
我曾经说过不会再有意外了
Pep, I know I said no more surprises...
可我真的希望能完成最后的这次任务
but I gotta say I was really hoping to pull off one last one.
但是现在看来…
But it looks like...
你也知道的
Well, you know what it looks like.
别太难过
Don't feel bad about this.
我的意思是你可以悲痛几个星期
I mean, actually, if you grovel for a couple weeks...
然后怀着自责继续生活
and then move on with enormous guilt...
我得躺下了 闭会儿眼睛
I should probably lie down for a minute. Go rest my eyes.
你要知道
Please know...
每天入睡的时候 这些天都一样
when I drift off, it'll be like every night lately.
我挺好的一切都挺好
I'm fine. Totally fine.
我会梦到你
I dream about you.
梦里一直都是你
Because it's always you.
我没能阻止他
Couldn't stop him.
我也没有
Neither could I.
那孩子牺牲了
I lost the kid.
托尼 我们都输了
Tony, we lost.
那么…
Is, uh...?
- 太好了 - 我的天
- Oh, good. - Oh, my God!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
没事儿了
It's okay.
灭霸离开地球己经二十三天了
It's been 23 days since Thanos came to Earth.
各国政府分崩离析
World governments are in pieces.
还在运转的部门正在做人口统计
The parts that are still working are trying to take a census
根据情况统计
...and it looks like he did...
看来他做的和他说的完全一致
He did exactly what he said he was gonna do.
灭霸夺走了…
Thanos wiped out...
一半的生命
...50% of all living creatures.
他现在在哪里
Where is he now? Where?
不知道
We don't know.
他打开了一扇传送门然后离开了
He just opened a portal and walked through.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他很生气
Oh, he's pissed.
他觉得自己失败了
He thinks he failed.
确实如此 但谁不是呢
Which, of course, he did, but there's a lot of that going around, ain't there?
说真的 你不开口说话
Honestly, until this exact second
我以为你是毛绒玩具呢
I thought you were a Build-A-Bear.
随你的便
Maybe I am.
我们三周来一直在搜寻灭霸的踪迹
We've been hunting Thanos for three weeks now.
宇宙空间卫星扫描一无所获
Deep space scans and satellites, and we got nothing.
托尼 你和他交过手
Tony, you fought him.
谁告诉你的 我没和他交过手
Who told you that? I didn't fight him.
他把一颗星球砸到我脸上
No, he wiped my face with a planet...
那个变戏法的就交出原石了
while the Bleecker Street magician gave away the stone.
事情就是这样 根本没法打 知道了
That's what happened. There was no fight,
打不过
'cause he's not beatable.
他有没有留下线索或坐标之类的
Did he give you any clues, any coordinates, anything?
我几年前就知道这一切
I saw this coming a few years back.
我早就料到了 我不敢相信
I had a vision. I didn't wanna believe it.
还以为是一场噩梦
Thought I was dreaming.
托尼 我需要你集中精神
Tony, I'm gonna need you to focus.
我需要过你
And I needed you.
那是以前了 比你现在更需要
As in, past tense. That trumps what you need.
一切都晚了 老兄 抱歉
It's too late, buddy. Sorry.
你知道我现在需要什么吗 我需要刮胡子
You know what I need? I need a shave.
而且我记得告诉过你们
And I believe I remember telling all youse...
托尼 托尼 托尼
Tony, Tony!
你们和那些不在的人
...alive and otherwise,
我们需要用战甲把全世界武装起来
that what we needed was a suit of armor around the world.
还记得吗
Remember that?
不管它是否侵犯了我们宝贵的自由
Whether it impacted our precious freedoms or not.
那才是我们真正需要的
That's what we needed.
那条路最后行不通
Well, that didn't work out, did it?
我说过我们会输的
I said we'd lose.
你说即使输了也一起面对
You said, "We'll do that together, too."
结果怎么样 队长 我们输了
And guess what, Cap? We lost.
而你当时根本不在
And you weren't there.
我们就这个水平吗 只能慢人一步吗
But that's what we do, right? Our best work after the fact?
我们只能当复仇者吗
We're the "Avengers."
只能当复仇者 不能当预防者吗
We're the "Avengers," not the "Pre-vengers."
- 行了 - 是不是啊
- Okay. - Right?
你说的够多了 坐下吧 好吧
You made your point. Just sit down, okay?
我还没说完
Okay. No, no, here's my point. You know what?
- 她就挺好 - 托尼 坐下吧
- She's great by the way. - Tony, you're sick. Sit down.
我们需要你 你是新生力量
We need you. You're new blood.
你们这帮老废物 我没什么可给你的
Bunch of tired old mules. I got nothing for you, Cap.
没有坐标 没有线索 没有战术 没有方案
I got no coordinates, no clues, no strategies, no options.
什么都没有 我也不相信你 你这个骗子
Zero. Zip. Nada. No trust, liar.
拿着这个
Here, take this.
你找到他以后 把这个戴上
You find him, you put that on...
然后躲起来
you hide.
- 托尼 - 我没事儿
- Tony! - I'm fine.
布鲁斯给了他一针镇静剂
Bruce gave him a sedative.
他今天可能醒不过来了
He's gonna probably be out for the rest of the day.
你们照顾好他
You guys take care of him...
我回来时给他带一瓶佐利安灵药
and I'll bring him a Xorrian elixir when I come back.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去杀灭霸
To kill Thanos.
我们一般都是团队作战
You know, we usually work as a team here...
再说现在士气也不高
and, uh, between you and I, morale's a little fragile.
我们知道太空是你的地盘
We realize up there is more your territory,
但这也是我们的战斗
but this is our fight, too.
你知道他到底在哪儿吗
You even know where he is?
我找人问就行
I know people who might.
没必要
Don't bother.
我可以告诉你们灭霸在哪里
I can tell you where Thanos is.
灭霸用了很长时间使我变得完美
Thanos spent a long time trying to perfect me.
他一直在给我讲述那个宏大的计划
And when he worked, he talked about his Great Plan.
即便被大卸八块 我也想讨好他
Even disassembled, I wanted to please him.
我就会问…
I'd ask...
大功告成以后 我们将何去何从
where would we go once his plan was complete?
他的回答永远只有一个
And his answer was always the same.
去那个花园
"To the Garden."
真够可以的 灭霸居然还有退休计划
That's cute. Thanos has a retirement plan.
所以他在哪儿
So, where is he?
灭霸打完响指后
When Thanos snapped his fingers...
地球成了宇宙级能量涌动的原爆点
Earth became ground zero for a power surge of ridiculously cosmic proportions.
从没有过这么大的能量
No one's ever seen anything like it.
直到两天以前
Until two days ago...
在这颗星球上
on this planet.
灭霸就在那里
Thanos is there.
他又用原石了
He used the stones again.
我们现在人手短缺吧
We'd be going in shorthanded, you know?
而且原石还在他手上 所以…
Look, he's still got the stones, so...
那就抢回来
So, let's get 'em.
把所有人救回来
Use them to bring everyone back.
就这么简单吗
Just like that?
对 就这么简单
Yeah. Just like that.
即便逆转这一切的希望渺茫
Even if there's a small chance that we can undo this...
为了逝去的战友 我们也必须竭尽全力去试试
I mean, we owe it to everyone who's not in this room to try.
如果我们这么做了
If we do this, how do we know
我们怎么知道结局会和之前不一样
it's gonna end any differently than it did before?
因为之前你们没有我
Because before you didn't have me.
嘿 新来的
Hey, new girl?
这个屋子里的人多少也都算超级英雄
Everybody in this room is about that superhero life.
我倒要问问这么长时间你去哪儿了
And if you don't mind my asking, where the hell have you been all this time?
宇宙里的星球很多
There are a lot of other planets in the universe.
可惜没有你们这样的人守护
And unfortunately, they didn't have you guys.
我觉得她不错
I like this one.
我们去干掉这个混蛋
Let's go get this son of a bitch.
复
仇
者
联
盟
终
局
之
战
好吧 谁没来过太空
Okay. Who here hasn't been to space?
怎么了
Why?
可别在我的船上吐出来
You better not throw up on my ship.
启动跳跃 三 二一
Approaching jump in three, two, one.
我先去侦察一下
I'll head down for recon.
我们会成功的 史蒂夫
This is gonna work, Steve.
我知道
I know it will.
除了成功我别无选择
'Cause I don't know what I'm gonna do if it doesn't.
没有卫星 没有舰船
No satellites. No ships. No armies.
没有军队 没有任何地面防御
No ground defenses of any kind.
只有他一个人
It's just him.
那就够了
And that's enough.
不
Oh, no.
原石在哪里
Where are they?
回答他的问题
Answer the question.
宇宙需要被校正
The universe required correction.
在那之后 原石除了诱惑再无他用
After that, the stones served no purpose beyond temptation.
你杀害了无数生命
You murdered trillions!
你们应该为之感恩
You should be grateful.
原石在哪里
Where are the stones?
不在了 一切归为尘埃
Gone. Reduced to atoms.
你两天前才刚刚用过
You used them two days ago!
我使用原石摧毁了原石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
这几乎要了我的命
It nearly killed me.
但我的使命完成了
But the work is done.
注定如此
It always will be.
我就是…天命
I am inevitable.
我们好好找找 他肯定在说谎
We have to tear this place apart. He has to be lying!
我父亲什么都干得出来
My father is many things.
但他从不说谎
A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你 女儿
Thank you, daughter.
也许我对你太苛刻了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
什么
What?
你干了什么
What did you do?
这次我是冲着头去的
I went for the head.
五
年
后
所以 我…
So...
他们不在了,
我们何去何从?
我约人出去吃了个饭
...I, uh, went on a date the other day.
五年以来第一次
It's the first time in five years.
我坐在餐桌那里 不知道该说些什么
You know? I'm sitting there at dinner. I didn't even know what to talk about.
你们聊了什么
What did you talk about?
还是那些废话 一切都变了
Eh, same old crap. You know, how things have changed.
我的工作 他的工作
My job, his job.
我们有多么想念大都会球队
How much we miss the Mets.
后来我们都沉默了
And then things got quiet...
然后他在上沙拉的时候哭了
then he cried as they were serving the salads.
那你呢
What about you?
我也哭了 在上甜点的时候
I cried just before dessert.
但是我们明天还会见面 所以…
But I'm seeing him again tomorrow, so...
很好 你克服了最艰难的时刻
That's great.
虽然不知道结果会怎么样
You did the hardest part. You took the jump.
你还是迈出了新的一步
You didn't know where you were gonna come down.
就是这样 我们总要迈出这样的一小步
And that's it. That's those little brave baby steps we gotta take...
让我们重新振作起来 重新找到方向
to try and become whole again, try and find purpose.
1945年我被封在冰里
I went in the ice in '45,
那之前我刚遇到一生至爱
right after I met the love of my life.
直到七十年后我才醒来
Woke up 70 years later.
但是你必须要继续前行
You gotta move on.
继续生活
Gotta move on.
世界的命运在你我手中
The world is in our hands.
这是我们的使命 我们责无旁贷
It's left to us, guys. And we gotta do something with it.
否则…
Otherwise...
灭霸本可以杀掉我们所有人
Thanos should've killed all of us.